（結衣）はあ　はあ…
＜あれから　もう１週間＞
It's been a week since then.
My saving your dog was just a coincidence.
《（比企谷）お前んちの犬
助けたのは偶然だし》
I'm pretty sure I'd've still turned out a loner, even if it hadn't happened.
《あの事故がなくても
俺　多分　ぼっちだったし》
If you were being nice to me out of guilt, then just drop it.
《気にして優しくしてんなら…
そんなのはやめろ》
＜何で　こうなっちゃったんだろう＞
How did it end up this way?
Jerk.
バカ…
（サブレが鳴きだす）
Wait, Sablé!
ちょっと　サブレ！
♪♪～
暑～ッ
It's so hot!
あッ
おッ
うす…
あッ　うん
Hey.
H-Hi.
＜オーケー　超クール
完全にリセットできている＞
Okay, cool.
We're totally reset.
By resetting our relationship, I've regained my peace of mind,
＜お互いの関係性をリセットすることで
俺は心の平穏を取り戻し＞
and Yuigahama has been freed from the chains of guilt
＜由比ヶ浜は負い目から解放され＞
＜元のリア充ライフへと回帰する＞
and can now return to her original fulfilling life.
I didn't make the wrong decision.
＜選択肢として
間違っちゃいないはずだ＞
My decision was as right as they come.
＜いや　むしろ正しい＞
＜だから　この件は　これで終わり＞
And so, that's the end of that.
＜リセットして　また
お互いの日常を過ごせばいい＞
We reset, and return to our separate lives.
＜人生はリセットできないが
人間関係はリセットできる＞
You can't reset your life, but you can reset your relationships.
＜ソースは俺　中学の同級生とか
１人も連絡　取ってな…＞
I'm the source on that.
Like how I haven't talked
to anyone from middle school—
＜それはリセットじゃなくて
デリートでした　テヘッ＞
That wasn't a reset, that was a delete.
（雪乃）あなた　由比ヶ浜さんと
何かあったの？
Did you do something to Yuigahama-san?
いや　何も
Nope. Nothing.
I doubt that Yuigahama-san would stop coming unless something happened between you two.
何もなかったら　由比ヶ浜さんは
来なくなったりしないと思うけど
Did you two have a fight?
ケンカでもしたの？
いや　してない…　と思うが
No, we didn't.
At least, I think.
大体　ケンカなんて　それなりに
近しい連中がすることだろ？
Besides, only people who
are somewhat close can have fights.
だから　ケンカっつーより…
いさかい　とか？
It's less of a fight and more of a...
An argument?
当たらずとも遠からずって感じか
Not quite. You're warm, though.
A war, then?
じゃあ　戦争？
当たってないし　遠くなったな
No, now you're getting colder.
Total war, then.
なら　せん滅戦
話聞いてた？　遠くなったよ
Sorry, were you listening? Colder.
すれ違い　というやつかしらね
A difference of opinions?
そんな感じだな
Something like that.
I see. Then there isn't much else to say.
そう…　なら仕方ないわね
（平塚）何だ　由比ヶ浜は
今日もいないのか？
Oh, so Yuigahama didn't come today either?
先生　ノックを
Sensei, knock, please.
彼女には　それなりに
期待していたのだがなあ　ああ～
I was expecting great things out of her too.
あの　先生
何か用があったんじゃ？
Hey, Sensei.
Didn't you come here to do something?
ああ　そうだ　比企谷
例の勝負だが
Oh, right, Hikigaya!
About the contest—let's go with a battle royale.
これからは
バトルロワイヤルでいこう
バトルロワイヤル！？　２人だけで？
A battle royale? With just two people?
≪（平塚）必要なら　新入部員を
勧誘してもかまわない
If you need to, you can go recruit new members.
Doesn't look like Yuigahama's
coming back, after all.
由比ヶ浜は　もう来ないようだしな
Yuigahama-san hasn't quit the club—
由比ヶ浜さんは　やめたわけでは…
来ないのなら同じだよ
If she isn't coming, she may as well have.
やる気がない者に　構ってやるのは
義務教育まで→
We only waste time with unmotivated students in compulsory education.
If you have not the will,
you can naught but leave.
意志なき者は去るほかない
Um...
あッ　あの～
I'm not motivated, and I don't have the will to be here. Can I leave?
俺　やる気も意志もないんで
去ってもいいですか？　おッ…
でッ　ですよね
Y-Yeah, thought so.
まッ　しかし　由比ヶ浜のおかげで
部員が増えると
In any case,
thanks to Yuigahama, now we know that you guys are more active when you've got more members.
部の活動が
活発化することは分かった
いい機会だ　君達は月曜までに
少なくとも　もう１人→
This is a good opportunity!
Get at least one more member by next Monday.
やる気と意志を持った者を確保し
人員補充したまえ
Find someone with the motivation and the will to replenish your human resources.
何なら
If you're so inclined,
今から
you can start now.
This is tyranny.
おッ　横暴だ
心外だな
Rude much?
私なりの優しさのつもりだがね
I'm trying to be nice here.
平塚先生　一つ確認しますが
人員補充すればいいんですよね？
Hiratsuka-sensei, just so we're on the same page,
we simply need to replenish our human resources, correct?
Precisely, Yukinoshita.
そのとおりだよ　雪ノ下
I wish you luck.
健闘を祈る！
人員補充って
どうすりゃいいんだ
Replenish human resources?
How're we supposed to do that?
入ってくれそうな人に
心当たりならあるわ
I have someone in mind who might join.
誰　戸塚？
戸塚か…　戸塚だよな？
Who? Totsuka?
Totsuka, huh?
Totsuka, right?
由比ヶ浜さんよ
Yuigahama-san.
Wait, but she's quitting, right?
いや　だって　やめるんでそ？
だったら　もう一度
入り直せばいいだけでしょう
Then we just need her to join again.
平塚先生は　人員の補充さえ
できればいいと言ってたわけだし
Hiratsuka-sensei said that we just had to replenish our human resources.
けど　簡単に戻ってくるか？
But you think she'd just come back?
離れていったら
そのまんまってのが普通だぞ
Typically, once someone leaves, they're gone for good.
６月１８日　何の日か知ってる？
June 18.
Do you know what's on that day?
いいや
由比ヶ浜さんの誕生日よ　多分
No.
It's Yuigahama-san's birthday.
I think.
アドレスに０６１８って入っていたから
Her e-mail address ends with 0618.
直接　確認したことはないんだな？
うッ…
But you never asked her the actual date.
さすがのコミュニケーション能力
Yeah, great communication skills.
Anyway, I want to celebrate her birthday.
だから
誕生日のお祝いをしてあげたいの
たとえ今後　由比ヶ浜さんが
奉仕部へ来ないにしても
Even if she doesn't come back to the Service Club,
これまでの感謝は伝えたいから
そうか
I want her to know that I'm grateful to her.
I see.
ねえ　比企谷君
ああ？
Hey, Hikigaya-kun.
そッ　その…　あの
U-Um...
Er...
ええッ？
Huh?
C-Could you go out with me?
つッ　つきあってくれないかしら？
Huh?!
はあ？
ごめんなさいね　休日なのに
つきあわせてしまって
Sorry for asking you out on a weekend.
Oh, don't mention it!
（小町）いいえ　小町も結衣さんの
誕生日プレゼント　買いたいですし→
I wanna buy a present for Yui-san too!
And hanging out with you sounds like buckets of fun, Yukino-san!
雪乃さんと
お出かけ　楽しみですし
All right. Let's go for maximum efficiency.
効率重視でいこう
I'll take this side.
俺　こっち回る
では　私が反対側を受け持つわ
Then I'll take this side.
じゃあ　小町は　この奥のほう
Okay, Komachi, you've got that part of—
Stop right there.
ストップです
What was that for? That hurt like hell!
何だよ…　ていうか　指超痛え
When'll we get another chance like this? Let's shop together!
せっかくなので
みんなで回りませんか？
And we can make suggestions and stuff! It's better!
そのほうがアドバイスし合えるし
お得です
But we won't be able to cover the whole mall.
けれど　それだと
回りきれないんじゃないかしら
Don't worry.
大丈夫です　小町の見立てだと
結衣さんの趣味的には→
My senses tell me that we can find stuff Yui-san likes...
ここの辺りを押さえておけば
問題ないと思います！
if we just cover this section here!
小町…　この辺りでいいんだよな？
Komachi.
This is the section, right?
あれ　小町　見なかったか？
Huh?
Did you see where she went?
（呼び出し中）
Hi, hi!
[TEL]（小町）はいは～い
お前　今　どこにいんだよ
Hey, where'd you go?
Oh, there's a ton of stuff I wanna buy, so I totally forgot about you.
[TEL]小町　買いたいもの色々あるから
すっかり忘れてたよ
You were the one who wanted to shop together!
みんなで回りましょうって
言ったのは　お前だろ
I never imagined my sister could be this much of an airhead.
妹の頭が　ここまで
残念なことになっていたとは…
お兄ちゃん　ちょっとショックだよ
I worry about you.
[TEL]はあ…　お兄ちゃんに
分かれっていうほうが無理か
Yeah, guess you can't take a hint, Onii-chan.
What the hell are you trying to say?
何が言いてえんだよ
[TEL]まあ　いいや
Nothing! I'm gonna take another five hours or so, and I can find my own way home,
[TEL]小町　あと５時間ぐらい
かかりそうだし
[TEL]何なら　１人で帰るから
あとは２人で頑張って！
so good luck, you two!
（電話が切れる）
Hey!
Why would I need luck to buy something?
もの買うのに
頑張るもなにもねえだろ…
雪ノ下…
Yukinoshita?
小町さん　どうしたって？
So where did Komachi-san go?
ああ　いや
何か　買いたいものがあるらしい
Oh, she said she had stuff to buy.
で　あとは丸投げされた
So we're stuck present-hunting by ourselves.
そもそも
休日に　つきあわせているのだし
We asked her for her time on a weekend.
She has a right to complain. We don't.
文句が言えた義理ではないわね
あとは私達で何とかしましょう
We'll have to manage on our own.
（店員）ありがとうございました
Thank you very much!
行きましょう
Let's go.
（せき払い）
Do I look that shady?
俺　そんなに不審かな？
どうやら　このエリアだと
男性の１人客は警戒されるようね
It seems people are wary of lone male shoppers in this part of the mall.
Not much I can do around here, then.
俺が　ここにいても
できることはなさそうだな
俺　あっちのほうにいるから
I'll wait for you over there—
Wait.
待ちなさい
ああ？
You want me to choose a present based on my judgment alone?
私のセンスに任せるつもり？
自慢ではないけれど
I don't mean to brag,
私は一般の女子高生と
離れた価値基準を持っているのよ
but I have a very different sense of worth from your typical high school girl.
自覚はあったんだな
So you knew?
だから　その…
So, um...
手伝ってもらえると
助かるのだけれど
I'd like you to assist me.
＜でも　俺も女子にプレゼンして
惨敗した覚えはあるが＞
I've messed up giving a presentation in front of girls before,
＜プレゼント買ったことなんてないぞ＞
but I've never bought a present for one in my life.
まあ　でも
店の中　入れないしな
But I can't exactly go into these stores.
はあ…　この際　仕方ないわ
あまり距離をあけないようにして
I guess we have no choice.
Try not to put too much distance between us.
はあ　距離？
言わなければ分からないの？
Huh? Distance?
Do I have to spell everything out for you?
あなた　空気を吸って
吐くだけしかできないなら
If all you're good for is taking in air and blowing it back out,
そこらのエアコンのほうが
よほど優秀よ
a common air conditioner is far more skilled than you.
＜確かに空気読む機能とかもあれば
超便利＞
Yeah, it would be a lot easier if I could sense tension in it too.
つまり　今日一日に限り
Basically, I will permit you to act as though you were my boyfriend today and today alone.
恋人のように振る舞うことを
許可する　ということよ
すげえ　上から目線だな
Wow, that sounded really condescending.
何か不満でも？
別に不満はねえよ
Do you have a problem with that?
No, not really.
そッ　そう…
I-I see.
＜別に
驚かれるようなことじゃない＞
Nothing to be surprised about.
＜こいつの恋人など　ごめんだが
雪ノ下は嘘をつかない＞
I wouldn't date her even if she were the last girl on Earth,
but Yukinoshita can't lie.
＜フリといえば　間違いなくフリだ
だから　勘違いのしようがない＞
When she says "act," she really means act.
There's no room for misunderstanding.
あなたは
てっきり嫌がると思ったけれど
I was convinced you would be hostile to the suggestion.
No. No reason for me to refuse it, anyway.
いや　特に断る理由もないしな
つーか　お前は嫌じゃないのかよ
And aren't you hostile to it?
別に　かまわないわよ
周囲に他人しかいない状況なら
I have no reason to be.
Considering that everyone around us are complete strangers,
勘違いされて
風評被害にあう心配もないもの
I have no reason to believe that my reputation could be damaged through a misunderstanding.
grooming
このままじゃダメだよね
やっぱり　ちゃんと話　しなきゃね
I can't let things sit the way they are.
I have to talk it through with him.
クッキーだって
ちゃんと渡せてない…　あッ！？
I couldn't give him the cookies in the end, either.
うえ～ッ
事務用品
選んでんじゃないんだから
We're not shopping for office supplies here.
You'll never settle on a dress if all you're looking at is durability.
耐久性とかで服を選んでたら
一生　決まんないと思うぞ
And I doubt Yuigahama's looking for a defense bonus in her clothes, either.
由比ヶ浜　多分　服に
防御力とか求めてないだろうし
仕方がないじゃない
What am I supposed to do?
材質や縫製くらいでしか
判断がつかないのよ
I can't judge them based on anything but material and manufacturing quality.
私　由比ヶ浜さんが何が好きとか
どんなものが趣味とか…
I don't know what Yuigahama-san likes, or what her hobbies are.
知らなかったのね
Do you really need to know?
別に知らんくていいだろ
むしろ半端な情報だけで
知った顔されたら腹が立つ
If someone acted like they knew exactly what I wanted based on general tastes, I'd get pissed.
千葉県民に向かって　よその落花生
おくるようなもんだ
It's like giving someone from Chiba Prefecture peanuts from another prefecture.
たとえが千葉すぎて
分からないのだけれど…
That analogy was too Chiba for me to understand.
It's like sending a sommelier wine without being an expert yourself.
ソムリエに半端な知識で
ワイン　おくるみてえなことだよ
なるほど　そういうことなら
I see.
If that's the case...
どうかしら？
What do you think?
どうって言われてもなあ
すげえ　よく似合ってるとしか…
I don't know what to say,
other than, "Wow, it looks great on you."
そう　ありがとう
I see. Thank you.
けれど　私のことではなくて
But I wasn't asking about me.
由比ヶ浜さんに　どうかしら
という意味よ
I was asking how Yuigahama-san would like it.
Don't you think Yuigahama would like something more fancy and frilly
由比ヶ浜は　何かもっと
フワフワポワポワした
頭の悪そうなもののほうが
喜ぶんじゃないの？
that someone with a lower IQ would wear?
ひどい言いぐさだけれど
的確だから反応に困るわね
That's a very rude way to put it,
but it's so accurate that I'm not sure how to respond.
これにするわ
いいんじゃないの　もう何でも
I'll get this for her.
Hey, why not? Whatever rocks your socks.
それも買うのか…
You're buying that one too?
（陽乃）あれ　雪乃ちゃん？
Huh? Yukino-chan?
あッ　やっぱり　雪乃ちゃんだ
Oh, I knew it! It is you!
姉さん…
はあ　姉さん？
Nee-san?
Huh?! "Nee-san"?!
Huh?!
雪乃ちゃんの姉・陽乃です
あなた　お名前は？
I'm Yukino-chan's older sister, Haruno.
What's your name?
はあ…　比企谷です
Uh... Hikigaya.
比企谷…　へえ～
Hikigaya? Hm...
Hikigaya-kun, huh?
比企谷君ね　うん！　よろしくね→
Okay, nice to meet you!
２人は　いつから
つきあってるんですか～？
When'd you two start dating?
Come on, come on! Tell me!
ほれほれ　言っちゃえよ～
We're just in the same grade.
ただの同級生よ
彼氏じゃないですけど
I'm not her boyfriend.
おッ　君もムキになっちゃってえ→
Look at you, getting all flustered!
Make Yukino-chan cry, and I'll make sure you regret it!
雪乃ちゃんを泣かせたりしたら
お姉ちゃん　許さないぞ～
Hey, that hurts!
＜ちょ　ちょッ　痛えっつーか＞
And get off me! Get off me! Get off me!
＜近い近い近いって…　いい匂い＞
Hey, she smells nice.
姉さん　いい加減にしてちょうだい
Nee-san, could you stop that, please?
ああ　ごめんね　お姉ちゃん
ちょっと調子に乗りすぎたかも
Oh, sorry.
I may have gone a little overboard.
雪乃ちゃん　繊細な性格の子だから
比企谷君が気をつけてあげてね
Yukino-chan's actually very delicate,
so you'd better be careful with her, 'kay?
私　今　嫌がられるようなこと
しちゃったかな？
Did I do something you didn't like?
Oh, no, uh...
ああ　ほら　その
俺　耳弱いんで
My ears are sensitive.
比企谷君　初対面の女性に
性癖をさらすのはやめなさい
Hikigaya-kun, I'd recommend against revealing your fetishes to women you've only just met.
訴えられても　文句言えないわよ
You may find yourself receiving a summons.
比企谷君　すっごい面白～い
Wow, Hikigaya-kun, you're so funny!
もういいかしら　特に用がないなら
私達は　もう行くけれど
May we leave now?
If you have no business with us, we'd like to leave.
Hikigaya-kun, if you ever start dating Yukino-chan for real, we should have a drink!
比企谷君　雪乃ちゃんの
彼氏になったら　お茶しようね
お前の姉ちゃん　すげえな
Your sister's amazing.
姉に会った人は皆　そう言うわね
Everyone who meets her says the same.
確かに　あれほど完璧な存在も
いないでしょう
Indeed, you probably won't find another woman as perfect as her.
誰もが　あの人を褒めそやす
はあ？
Everyone sings her praises.
Huh?
そんなの　お前も
大して変わらんだろ
Sure, but we can say the same about you.
Use her to praise yourself?
遠回しな自慢か？
えッ？
Huh?
俺が
すげえっつってんのは　あの何？
What I found amazing was... How should I put it?
強化外骨格みてえな外面のことだ
That Fortified Armored Shell-like mask of hers.
人当たりがよくて
ずっとニコニコしてて
Acting all sociable and always smiling, starting conversations like a nice girl.
優しく話しかけてくれる
まさに男の理想だわな
Every man's ideal woman.
でも理想は理想だ　現実じゃない
But ideals are ideals.
They aren't reality.
だから　どこか嘘くさい
So it feels totally fake.
腐った目でも
いえ　腐った目だから
Despite your rotting eyes—
or perhaps you can see because they're rotten.
見抜けることがあるのね
お前　それ褒めてるの？
Is that supposed to be a compliment?
It is.
褒めてるわよ　絶賛したわ
I'm singing your praises.
（犬の鳴き声）
おお？
いッ　犬が…
A-A dog...
あッ！
H-Hikigaya-kun...
ひッ　比企谷君…
ほ～れ　おい　飼い主どうした？
Huh?
Hey, where's your owner?
Haven't they heard of a leash?
放し飼いかよ
Whoa!
うわッ　何だ　この犬
What's up with this dog?
なつきすぎじゃねえの？
It likes me way too much.
アウ～　ウ～
この犬…
ごめんなさ～い
This dog...
I'm so sorry!
ウチのサブレが　ご迷惑を…
My little Sablé just ran off and...
あら　由比ヶ浜さん
Oh? Yuigahama-san?
へッ？　あれ
ヒッキーと　ゆきのん？
Huh? Hikky and Yukinon?
え～ッ　何で一緒なの？
Huh?
Why are you here together?
何でって　別に…
Why? No reason.
あッ　やっぱいい！
大丈夫　何でもない
No, never mind! It's okay! Forget I asked!
休みの日に２人で出かけたら
そんなの決まってるよね　ヘヘヘ…
I mean, like, you two going out together on a weekend? It's totally obvious!
I see! Why didn't I, like, notice?
そっか
何で気づかなかったかな　あたし
空気　読むのだけが取り柄なのに
エヘヘ…
Noticing things was the only thing I was good at too!
＜こいつ　何か変な勘違いを…＞
I think she might have the wrong idea.
じゃ　じゃあ　あたし
もう行くから
W-Well, I'll be going now.
由比ヶ浜さん
私達のことで話があるから
Yuigahama-san, I want to tell you something about us.
月曜日　部室に来てくれるかしら？
Would you mind coming to the clubroom on Monday?
ああ～　アハハ
あんまり　聞きたくないかも
Um...
I might not really want to hear it.
その　今さら聞いても
どうしようもないっていうか
It's like, nothing'll change even if I do, right?
手も足も出ないっていうか…
Or, like, there's nothing I can do about it.
私　こういう性格だから
うまく伝えられなかったのだけど
Being the way I am, I didn't really know how to tell you before,
あなたには　キチンと
話しておきたいと思っているわ
but I do want to tell you properly.
うん…
Okay...
（深呼吸）
何してんだ？　お前
What are you doing?
うひゃ～！　ヒッ　ヒッキー
H-Hikky?!
W-Well, like... the air tasted great?
やッ　やあ～　その何？
空気が　おいしかったというか…
ほれ　行くぞ
Come on, let's go.
由比ヶ浜さん
Yuigahama-san.
やッ　やっはろー　ゆきのん
Y-Yahallo, Yukinon...
由比ヶ浜さん
Yuigahama-san.
あッ　あーっと
U-Um...
You wanted to tell me something about you and Hikky, right?
ゆッ　ゆきのんとヒッキーのことで
話があるんだよね…
ええ　私達の今後のことで
あなたに話を
Yes.
We wanted to tell you about our future—
H-Hey, you don't need to mind me at all!
やッ　やあ～　あたしのことなら
全然　気にしないでいいのに
そりゃ　確かにビックリしたっていうか
I mean, like, yeah, I was surprised at first,
but it was more because, like, we need to celebrate!
むしろ　お祝いとか祝福とか
そんな感じだし
H-How did you know?
よッ　よく分かったわね
そのお祝いをキチンとしたいの
I wanted to celebrate it.
それに　あなたには感謝してるから
Also, I'm very thankful to you.
H-Hey, I never did anything you need to thank me for!
ヤダな～　感謝されるようなこと
あたし　してないよ
何も　してない
I never did anything.
それでも　私は感謝している
Regardless, I'm still thankful to you.
それに　こうしたお祝いは
And celebrations like these don't happen because a celebrant asks.
本人が何かしたから
行われるものではないでしょう
純粋に私が　そうしたいだけよ
I simply want to celebrate.
うッ　うん…
Okay...
It feels like they aren't talking about the same thing.
＜何か　微妙に会話が
かみ合ってないような…＞
だッ　だから…　その
So... um...
それ以上　聞きたくないかも
I might not want to hear any more.
由比ヶ浜　お前
何か　勘違いしてねえか？
Yuigahama, I think
you're misunderstanding something here.
ちょッ　ちょっと待って！
W-Wait a second!
So you guys weren't dating or anything?
じゃ　２人は別に
つきあってたりとかしてないの？
そんなわけねえだろ
Like hell that'd happen!
Yuigahama-san, my fuse isn't infinitely long.
由比ヶ浜さん　私でも
怒ることあるのよ　大体　あの男に
In the first place, that man could never handle an interpersonal relationship,
まともな男女交際なんて
できるはずがないでしょう
そもそも
人との交際ができてないのに
let alone a relationship
with someone of the opposite sex.
ほっとけ　そんなめんどくせえ
交際なんてするか
Oh, shut up.
Like I'd ever want to be
in some stupid relationship.
夜中　泣きながら電話とか来たら
その時点で別れる自信あるぞ！
If some broad called me in the night, crying,
I'd break up with her right then and there.
あッ　ごめんごめん　あれ？
Sorry, sorry.
Huh?
お祝いの時間が
なくなってしまったわね
It seems we're out of time.
せっかくケーキを焼いてきたのに
I even baked a cake for you too.
A cake? Why a cake?
ケーキ…　何でケーキ？
何でって
Why?
今日は　由比ヶ浜さんの誕生日を
お祝いしたくて呼んだのよ
I asked you to come so we could celebrate your birthday.
はあ　おほッ？
由比ヶ浜さん　最近　部活に
来ていなかったし　慰労もかねて
You haven't been coming recently, but you've done a lot for the club.
あとは　その
感謝の証し　とでもいうのかしら
And... I guess you could call it a token of our appreciation.
プレゼントも！？
A present too?!
わあ～　ゆきのん！
Wow! Yukinon!
別に　私だけが
用意したわけではないけれど
I'm not the only one with a present for you.
へッ？
Huh?
アハハッ　まさかヒッキーが
プレゼント用意してるなんて
I never thought you'd get a present for me too, Hikky.
思わなかったな～
こないだから
ちょっと…　微妙だったし
I mean, we've been kinda... awkward recently?
悪い　誕生日だからって
わけじゃねえんだ
Sorry.
This isn't just for your birthday.
何つーか
これでチャラってことにしないか
How should I put it...
I was thinking we could call it even.
俺が　お前んちの犬　助けたのも
My saving your dog and
your feeling guilty about it...
それで　お前が気を使ってたのも
全部なし
Just forget it.
そもそも　俺が個人を特定して
恩を売ったわけじゃないんだから
I didn't do it to get any favors out of anyone in the first place,
お前が個人を特定して
恩を返す必要なんてないんだよ
so you don't need to return any favors to me.
けど　その　こう何…
So, uh... how to say it...
気を使ってもらってた分は
返しておきたい
I want to pay you back
for whatever you did out of guilt.
これで差し引きゼロでチャラ
Now any debts are paid and done.
もう　お前は
俺を気にかけなくていい
You don't need to be concerned about me anymore.
だから　これで終わりだろ　フウ…
So we can end all that now, right?
何で　そんなふうに思うの？
同情とか　気を使うとか
How can you think that?
I never thought of things in terms of pity or guilt.
そんなふうに思ったこと
一度もないよ
あたしは　ただ…
It's just that...
な～んか難しくて
よく分かんなくなってきちゃった
It's so complicated that I don't know what to call it anymore.
もっと簡単なことだと
思ったんだけどな…
It was a lot simpler in my head.
別に難しいことではないでしょう
I don't think it's a particularly difficult issue.
比企谷君には　由比ヶ浜さんを
助けた覚えはないし
Hikigaya-kun had no intention of helping Yuigahama-san.
由比ヶ浜さんも
比企谷君に同情した覚えはない
And Yuigahama-san has no recollection of ever pitying Hikigaya-kun.
始まりから　既に間違っているのよ
だから　比企谷君のいう
Everything was wrong from the start.
So I think Hikigaya-kun's decision to end it here is correct.
「終わりにする」という選択肢は
正しいと思う
でも　これで終わりだなんて
何か　ヤダよ
But I don't want anything to end here.
バカね　終わったのなら
また始めればいいじゃない
Silly.
Once it ends, you can begin all over again.
あなた達は悪くないのだし
はあ？
You're not the ones at fault, after all.
Huh?
あなた達は　助けた助けられたの
違いはあっても
While one of you saved and the other was saved,
等しく被害者なのでしょう？
both of you were victims.
なら　全ての原因は
加害者に求められるべきだわ
That means that the one who caused all of this is the malefactor.
どちらも悪くないのなら
初めから　もめる必要がないのよ
Neither of you was at fault, so there was no cause for argument in the first place.
だから　ちゃんと始めることだって
できるわ　あなた達は…
And so...
The two of you can begin anew properly.
あ…　私は平塚先生に
Oh, I need to report to Hiratsuka-sensei that we've replenished our human resources.
人員補充完了の報告を
してこないといけないから
（戸の開閉音）
ねえ　それ　開けていい？
Hey, can I open that?
お好きに　どうぞ
Be my guest.
（包みを開ける音）
わあ～　ねえ　似合うかな？
Wow!
Hey, how does it look?
エヘヘッ
H-Hold on a second...
ちょっと待て　いや　それ…
You know, that's...
犬の首輪なんだけど
a dog collar, right?
Huh?!
へッ？　先に言ってよ　バカ！
てッ…
T-Tell me that before I put it on! You jerk!
ほんっとに　もうッ
平塚先生んとこ行ってくる！
Seriously! Geez!
I'm telling Hiratsuka-sensei on you!
Thanks, jerk.
ありがと　バカ
Finally, His and Her Beginning Has Ended.
♪♪～
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities over summer break. Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
over summer break.
Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities over summer break. Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now.
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities over summer break. Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities over summer break. Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities over summer break. Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities over summer break. Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities over summer break. Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities over summer break. Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
Hikigaya-kun, I have an urgent announcement regarding the Service Club's activities over summer break. Please contact me at your earliest convenience.
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
You've noticed them, haven't you?
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
You've noticed them, right?
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
You've noticed them, right?
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
You've noticed them, right?
Are you still asleep?
I've sent a few texts and called you quite a few times now. You've noticed them, haven't you?
You've noticed them, right?
Answer the phone.
I'm afraid. Very afraid.
I'm afraid.
Very afraid
Next time:
Regardless, Not Getting
a Break Over Summer Break Is Wrong.
Regardless, Not Getting a Break Over Summer Break Is Wrong.
次回…